{"tossups": [{"question": "This deity wore an Atef crown decorated with ostrich feathers, and was fused with Apis to become Serapis in the Hellenic period. This \u201cforemost westerner\u2019s\u201d spine was represented by djed pillars after he was found in a lead-sealed box at Byblos by his wife, who retrieved this god\u2019s body after he was tricked by his brother, Set. For ten points, name this husband of Isis and father of Horus, the Egyptian god of the dead.", "answer": "<b> Osiris</b> (or<b> Asir</b>)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "This leader thanked \u201cthe grace of Ahura Mazda\u201d on the Behistun inscription. He ordered his lands into 20 satrapies, and this son of Cambyses II [cam-BYE-sees] built the Apadana at the ceremonial city of Persepolis. The Ionian Revolt targeted this ruler; in revenge, he launched an invasion that was stymied in 490 BC. For ten points, name this Persian emperor whose army was turned back at Marathon.", "answer": "<b> Darius I</b> or<b> Darius the Great</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "With David Scott, this man docked with an Agena vehicle, making<em> Gemini 8</em> the first docking of two orbiting spacecraft. This man, a retired U.S. Navy pilot upon becoming an astronaut, died in 2012. As the Command Module<em> Columbia</em> was piloted by Michael Collins, this man flew with Buzz Aldrin and took\u201cone small step for a man\u201d. For ten points, name this commander of the<em> Apollo 11</em> mission, the first man to walk on the Moon.", "answer": "Neil<b> Armstrong</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Thomas Henry Burge and Lord Frederick Cavendish were murdered in Phoenix Park in this city, and this city is home to a war memorial known as the Garden of Remembrance located on Parnell Square. It served as the capital of a free state until a 1937 constitution. The assassinations of the Cairo gang, a group of British intelligence officers, by the IRA sparked Bloody Sunday in this city. For ten points, name this capital of Ireland.", "answer": "<b> Dublin</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One of these compositions uses words by August Hoffmann and includes a second movement dedicated to wine, women, and song. One of these pieces shares a melody with The Moldau movement of Smetana\u2019s <em>Ma Vlast</em>. Another of these pieces uses the melody \u201cTo Anacreon in Heaven\u201d as the setting for a poem commemorating Fort McHenry\u2019s bombardment in the War of 1812 written by Francis Scott Key. For ten points, the Hatikvah, \u201cDeutchlandlied\u201d and \u201cThe Star-Spangled Banner\u201d are all what type of song, which is used to represent its country?", "answer": "<b> national anthem</b>s", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The Dutch built Fort Provintia on this island; today, Chihkan Tower stands at the former fort in the city of Tainan, which was this island\u2019s capital during the Qing [CHING] dynasty. This island, once known as Formosa, was the destination of Chiang Kai-shek\u2019s retreating Kuomintang. For ten points, name this island off the southeast coast of China, which disputes its sovereignty.", "answer": "<b> Taiwan</b> (or<b> Republic of China</b> or<b> Zhonghua Minguo</b>; accept<b> Formosa</b> before mentioned; do not accept or prompt China alone, Zhonghua alone, or the People\u2019s Republic of China)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Amos Akerman and Benjamin Bristow were appointed by this President as part of the Department of Justice, which this man created. This man put down the 1874 Brooks-Baxter War between two factions of the Republican Party. The Force Acts were passed by this President to safeguard African-Americans\u2019right to vote, and the end of his term marked the end of the Reconstruction Era. For ten points, name this U.S. President, a former general nicknamed \u201cUnconditional Surrender\u201d for his role in the U.S. Civil War.", "answer": "Ulysses S.<b> Grant</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The election of Stephen Langton to one post led to the signing of this document, which was supported by the Charter of the Forest. One clause from this document formed a council of 25 nobles to ensure its enforcement while another dealt with the removal of fish weirs. This document was proposed after a ruler lost the Battle of Bouvines and signed at Runnymede. For ten points, name this 1215 document signed by King John of England which granted rights to barons.", "answer": "<b> Magna Carta</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The last U.S. battleship to be completed was named for this state and christened by Margaret, the daughter of a then-Senator from this state. That battleship, now a museum next to the<em> USS Arizona</em> memorial, sailed to Tokyo for the signing of the Japanese surrender ending World War II. For ten points, name this U.S. state where Harry Truman lived in Independence, just outside Kansas City.", "answer": "<b> Missouri</b> (accept<b> USS Missouri</b>) <b>Second Quarter</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The leader who sent this force quipped that \u201cHe sent [this] against men, not God\u2019s wind and waves\u201d. This entity, which was directed by the Duke of Medina Sidonia, fared poorly against \u201cHell burners\u201d, and was defeated at the Battle of Gravelines. This entity\u2019s failure was attributed to the \u201cProtestant Wind\u201d, and it was sent to force one country to stop supporting Dutch rebels in the Eighty Years War. For ten points, name this massive naval fleet commanded by Phillip II whose goal was to invade England.", "answer": "<b> Spanish Armada</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "H.L. Barnum argued that this author\u2019s character Harvey Birch, the protagonist of<em> The Spy</em>, was based on the American Revolution soldier Enoch Crosby. This man\u2019s best known work is a fictionalization of the defense of Fort William Henry during the French and Indian War and features Chingachgook as the title character. For ten points, name this author of<em> The Leatherstocking Tales</em>, the most famous of which was<em> The Last of the Mohicans</em>.", "answer": "James Fenimore<b> Cooper</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "The first prototype of these objects was constructed by William Foster & Co., and nicknamed Little Willie. Modified versions of these objects, including Crocodiles and Crabs, carried flails and laid bridges and were named Hobart\u2019s Funnies. The Landship Commission developed the Mark line of these objects, which were first used in the Battle of Cambrai. Developed in response to stagnant trench warfare in WWI, for ten points, what vehicles, such as the M4 Sherman, use tracks instead of wheels and have a lot of armor?", "answer": "<b> Tanks</b> (accept<b> landships</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A hill creatively named Cornhill provided much of the early food for this colony, which was founded near Cole\u2019s Hill. Josiah Cotton served as this colony\u2019s Register of Deeds for some time. Its militia was run by Miles Standish, and William Bradford served as governor for this colony. For ten points, what early colony was founded by Pilgrims attempting to find Virginia by sailing on the<em> Mayflower</em>?", "answer": "<b> Plymouth</b> Colony", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The Minnesota case of<em> Baker v. Nelson</em> upheld a statute forbidding this action. The 12th anniversary of<em> Lawrence v. Texas</em> coincided with the decision in a Supreme Court case that legalized this practice. <em>U.S. v. Windsor</em> struck down Section 3 of DOMA, which allowed states to reject these events until 2013. For ten points, name this social right made legal in all 50 states by 2015\u2019s<em> Obergefell v Hodges</em>.", "answer": "<b> same-sex marriage</b> (or<b> gay marriage</b>; accept descriptive answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this Southern California city home to baseball\u2019s Padres and, for possibly not much longer, football\u2019s Chargers.", "answer": "<b> San Diego</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "The Catonsville Nine were Catholic activists who protested this war. The case<em> Tinker v. Des Moines</em> protected students\u2019 rights to protest against this war in schools. Napalm was heavily used in aerial offensives during this war, which saw large use of Agent Orange to destroy foliage. For ten points, name this Southeast Asian war won in 1975 by a Communist country once led by Ho Chi Minh.", "answer": "<b> Vietnam</b> War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Roswell Field took over a</b><em><b> pro bono</b></em><b> defense for this case after the death of David Hall. Benjamin Curtis and John McLean dissented in this case, which concerned the defendant\u2019s</b> <b>time spent in (+)</b> <b>Wisconsin.</b> <b>Roger Taney\u2019s [TAW-nee\u2019s] decision in this case was a</b> <b>Roger Taney\u2019s [TAW-nee\u2019s] decision in this case was a</b> <b>Roger Taney\u2019s [TAW-nee\u2019s] decision in this case was a</b> <b>dismissal on grounds that the defendant could not legally (*)</b> <b>dismissal on grounds that the defendant could not legally (*)</b> <b>dismissal on grounds that the defendant could not legally (*)</b> file a lawsuit. The Missouri Compromise was ruled unconstitutional by, for ten points, what 1857 Supreme Court case that ruled African-Americans were not U.S. citizens?", "answer": "<b> Dred Scott</b> v. James F. A. Sanford (or<b> Dred Scott</b> v. Sandford)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 2008, 300,000 people in this country were injured when melamine was added to food, particularly infant formula. In 2010, the US Embassy in this country\u2019s capital tweeted that its AQI reached 700, briefly calling it \u201ccrazy bad.\u201d The 2002-03 (+) SARS outbreak began in this country, where almost 70,000 people were killed by the 2008 (*) </b> Sichaun earthquake. For ten points, name this country where factories were shut down to clear the air prior to the 2008 Summer Olympics in Beijing.", "answer": "People\u2019s Republic of<b> China</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This editor of the</b><em><b> Avanti!</b></em><b> newspaper threatened to invade Greece in the Corfu Affair and saw members of Parliament leave after supporters of his party killed Giacomo (+) Matteotti. This leader allied with Adolf Hitler by signing the Pact of Steel, 17 years after forcing Victor (*) </b> Emmanuel III to name him as Prime Minister after leading the Blackshirts in a March on Rome. For ten points, name this Fascist Italian Prime Minister during World War II.", "answer": "Benito<b> Mussolini</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>During this event, over a dozen people died in the Doolough Tragedy in County</b> <b>Mayo. This event was exacerbated by over-reliance on the Lumper and was triggered</b> <b>by</b><em><b> phytophthora infestans</b></em><b>. Lord John (+)</b> <b>Russell failed to respond to this event,</b> <b>which Robert Peel\u2019s repealing of the Corn Laws tried to remedy. Over one (*)</b> million people died during, for ten points, what 19th century agricultural disaster caused by a blight on a staple crop in Ireland?", "answer": "<b> Irish Potato Famine</b> (or<b> Great Famine</b> or<b> Great Hunger</b>; \u201cIrish\u201d not needed after \u201cIreland\u201d is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}